A Guide to the J. T. Shropshire papers, 1955-2005
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
J. T. Shropshire papers, 1955-2005
The Library of Virginia
51313
8 cu. ft. and 20 boxes
J. T. Shropshire
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Anne and Richard Shropshire of Richmond, Virginia.
Biographical Information
Jonah Thomas "Jay" Shropshire was born 25 April 1945 in Martinsville, Henry County, Virginia, to J. E. and Verna Shropshire. He graduated from Martinsville High School in 1963. Shropshire received a management degree from the National Business College in Roanoke, Virginia, and attended the University of Richmond. He received a Masters of Business Administration from the College of William and Mary in 1987. Shropshire worked as minute clerk and committee clerk for the Virginia House of Delegates from 1967 to 1971 and as assistant talley clerk for the majority party in the U.S. House of Representatives from 1971 to 1972. He became deputy clerk of the Senate of Virginia in 1972, and in 1976 was elected clerk of the Senate, a position he held until 1990. Shropshire was appointed chairman of the State Compensation Board by Governor Charles Robb in 1982 and reappointed by Governor Gerald Baliles in 1986. Governor L. Douglas Wilder appointed Shropshire his chief of staff in 1990. In 1994 Shropshire entered private business running a consulting firm. He married Anne Gravely and they had one child. Shropshire died in Loudoun County, Virginia, 23 May 2004, and was buried in Roselawn Burial Park in Martinsville.
Scope and Content
Papers, 1955-2005, of J. T. "Jay" Shropshire (1945-2004) of Henry and Loudoun Counties and Richmond, Virginia, concerning Shropshire's service as the clerk of the Virginia Senate, as the chairman of the Virginia State Compensation Board, and as the Chief of Staff for Governor L. Douglas Wilder. Papers also cover Shropshire's political activities in the state Democratic Party, as well as his personal life. Papers include address books, articles, bumper stickers, business cards, calendars, campaign buttons, clippings, correspondence, diaries, ephemera, magazines, oaths, photographs, records, reports, resumes, speeches, video cassettes, and other papers and items.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the following series:
Series I: Clerk of the Senate, 1975-1990
Series II: Compensation Board, 1982-1989
Series III: Chief of Staff, 1989-1994
Series IV: Personal Papers, 1967-2005
Series V: Politics, 1973-1992
Series VI: Diaries and address books, 1979-1898, 1995-2003
Series VII: Inaugurals, 1966-2005
Series VIII: Photographs, 1955-1991, undated
Series IX: Publications, 1962, 1970-1994, 2003-2005
Series X: General Papers, 1982-1997, undated
Series XI: Videocassettes, Campaign Buttons, and Ephemera
Contents List
- Series I: Clerk of the Senate, 1975-1990., Extent: 4 boxes. (Box 1-4)
  Clerk of the Senate, 1975-1990, papers consist of budgets, clippings, correspondence, forms, invitations, invoices, legislative bills, manuals, memoranda, programs, reports, resumes, stationery, and other papers detailing J. T. Shropshire's term as Clerk of the Senate of Virginia from 1976 to 1990, and covering his working relationship with Virginia's senators, elected officials, citizens, organizations, and businesses.
  - Correspondence, 1975, 1977-1978. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1979. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1980. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1981. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1982. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, January-February 1983. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, March 1983. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, April 1983. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, May 1983. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, June-July 1983. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, August 1983. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, September-October 1983. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, November 1983. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, December, no date, 1983. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, January-February 1984. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, March 1984. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, April 1984. (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, May 1984. (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence, June-July 1984. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, August-September 1984. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, October 1984. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, November-December 1984. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1985. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, January-February 1986. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, March 1986. (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, April 1986. (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, May 1986. (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, June 1986. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1 July 1986. (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, July-August 1986. (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, September-October 1986. (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, November 1986. (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, December, no date, 1986. (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, 1987. (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, January-September 1988. (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, October 1988. (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence from students, 14-16 November 1988. (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, November-December, no date, 1988. (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence, January-April 1989. (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence, May-August 1989. (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence, September-November 1989. (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence, December 1989-January 1990. (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence, no date. (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Memoranda, 1979, 1982. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Memoranda, January 1983. (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Memoranda, March-April, no date, 1983. (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Memoranda, 1984-1986. (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Memoranda, 1987-1989. (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Virginia Senate Procedures Manual. (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - State government organization, 1983, 1986. (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Votes in Virginia Senate including 1976 vote for clerk, 1976, 1983, undated. (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Excerpts from Senate journal, 1976, 1981, 1987. (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Virginia State Library (Library of Virginia) Foundation papers, 1984. (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - A New Proposal for Regulatory Reform: Administrative Law Judges--Gerald Baliles, Attorney General of Virginia and the Governor's Regulatory Reform Advisory Board, 25 September 1984. (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - House bill no. 735 amendment in the nature of a substitute--regarding the Virginia Supplemental Retirement Act, the State Police Officers Retirement Act, the Judicial Retirement Act, and the taxation of certain benefits, 8 February 1986. (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Joint Subcommittee studying the comprehensive conflict of interest act, 14 October 1986. (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Joint Subcommittee studying the comprehensive conflict of interest act minutes, 29 October 1986. (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Analysis of the Baliles Commission report, 1987. (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Procurement law problems. (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Senate Finance Committee financial exhibit for 1986-1988. (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Carry forward request (for budget), 1989. (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Clerk's office papers for 1990-1992 budget. (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Clerks of the Senate, 1776-1956 (1976). (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Lists of senators, 1988-1989. (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Lists of officers in localities--treasurers, commonwealth's attorneys, commissioners of the revenue, clerks of the circuit court, and sheriffs. (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Telecommunications, 1982-1983, 1986, undated. (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Malfeasance phone calls, 1988. (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Travel expense reimbursement vouchers, 1983. (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Virginia Supplemental Retirement System for senate, October 1983. (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Salary information, 1986. (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Leave papers. (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Night of the Hunter--tribute to Hunter B. Andrews, 1989. (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Peter K. Babalas, 1981-1985. (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Peter K. Babalas, 1986. (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Peter K. Babalas, undated. (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Joe Canada--standing committees, subcommittees, and commissions, 1986. (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - The Man from Henry County script--A. L. Philpott. (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Edward Willey, 1978-1986. (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Statements by Senators (Willard J. Moody, Robert E. Russell) and Delegates (Joseph Benedetti) on issues and eulogy of William Griffith Purcell, 1976, 1983, 1986. (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Senate office controversy, 1987-1988. (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Governor's appointments, 5 March 1982. (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Cabinet appointments and chief of staff--order of interviews, applications, resumes, 1986. (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Resumes of persons interested in state goverment positions. (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - American Society of Legislative Clerks and Secretaries, 1983. (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - American Society of Legislative Clerks and Secretaries, 1984. (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - American Society of Legislative Clerks and Secretaries roster, 1989. (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - VACo (Virginia Association of Counties) 55th annual meeting, 12-14 November 1989. (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - National Conference of State Legislatures management development seminar, 2-6 December 1984. (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Television show on the capitol and the legislature, 1989. (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Programs. (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Sons of the American Revolution--George Mason stamp, 1983-1984. (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Business-Industry Political Action Committee. (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Louisiana Speaker of the House race and Louisiana Governor's trip to Paris, France, 1984. (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - General papers, 1979-1989, undated. (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Senate of Virginia stationery (blank). (Box 4, Folder 24)
- Series II: Compensation Board, 1982-1989., Extent: 3 boxes. (Box 5-7)
  Compensation Board, 1982-1989, contains analyses, articles, correspondence, financial records, forms, legal records, memoranda, newsletters, oaths, presentations, press releases, reports, and other papers regarding the Virginia State Compensation Board during J. T. Shropshire's tenure as chairman. The State Compensation Board papers concern budgets and finances for operations of court and law enforcement offices, and salaries and compensation for staff and employees of those offices.
  - Correspondence, 1982-1983. (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1984-1986. (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, January-November 1987. (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, December 1987. (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, January 1988. (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, February-April 1988. (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, May 1988. (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, June-July 1988. (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, August 1988. (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, September-November 1988. (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, December 1988. (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, January 1989. (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, February-April 1989. (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, May 1989. (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, June 1989. (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, July 1989. (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, August 1989. (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, September 1989. (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, October-December 1989. (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Memoranda, 1987-1988. (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Memoranda, 27 January 1989. (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Memoranda, March-November 1989. (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Appeals. (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Objections, appeals, requests from localities. (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Suits filed against board. (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Dockets, 1987-1989. (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Unpaid Fines, Court Costs, and Restitution in District and Circuit Courts of the Commonwealth, December 1987. (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Compensation Board presentation tot the Senate Finance Subcommittee on Compensation and General Government, 1 February 1988. (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Prioritization of Jail Post Audit Positions for Overcrowded Jails--Adult Community Facilities, Divison of Adult Community Corrections, Department of Corrections, 17 June 1988. (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Interim Report: Status of Part-Time Commonwealth's Attorneys--Joint Legislative Audit and Review Commission, 15 November 1988. (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Compensation Board Information Needs Analysis--Virginia Department of Information Technology, November 1988. (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - The Alexandria Pretrial Release Program, 16 December 1988. (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Remarks, press releases, newsletters, articles, 1988-1989. (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Incarceration charts and statistics. (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Joint Legislative Audit and Review Commission Reports--surveys of commonwealth's attorneys (full and part-time) and circuit court judges. (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Printouts regarding positons--jail and law enforcement (folder 1 of 2). (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Printouts regarding positions--jail and law enforcement (folder 2 of 2). (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Locality financial data on jail and law enforcement positions. (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Budget information, 1983-1984, 1988-1990. (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Constitutional officers meeting minutes, 16-17 July 1989. (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Local government officials conference, 1988. (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Forms, 1985-1989. (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - General papers. (Box 7, Folder 8)
- Series III: Chief of Staff, 1989-1994., Extent: 2 boxes. (Box 7-8)
  Chief of Staff, 1989-1994, contains papers regarding J. T. Shropshire's role as the Chief of Staff for Governor Doug Wilder and discusses the operations of the Governor's Office, the Governor's schedule, the Virginia Retirement System, Wilder's relationship with Charles Robb, Wilder's decision to run for president in 1992, recording scandals, and interviews regarding the shooting death of Robert Lindsley (d. 1990) of Virginia Beach, Virginia. Papers consist of correspondence, directories, interviews, invitations, manuals, memoranda, notes, photographs, press releases, schedules, summaries, transcripts, and other papers.
  - Papers, 14-15 December 1989. (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Papers, 18-20 December 1989. (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Papers, 21-27 December, undated [December] 1989. (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Papers, January 1990. (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Papers, February-October 1990. (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Papers, 1991. (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Papers, 1992. (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Papers, 1993-1994. (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Papers, undated. (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Statement of ecomonic interest (J. T. Shropshire). (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - The Many Roles of the Governor's Chief of Staff, National Governors Association. (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Delegation of powers (suggested), 11 June 1990. (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Directory for staff, cabinet, agencies, Congress, General Assembly, and other state governors. (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Governor's news summary, 29 October 1992. (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Planning session notes, 17 December 1992. (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Governor's schedule, 6-17 January 1993. (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Virginia Retirement System--attorney general report and related correspondence, 23-24 November 1992. (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Wilder-Robb, 1991. (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Charles Hamel monitored calls, 1991. (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Shropshire polygraph, 3 September 1992. (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Robert Lindsley case--correspondence (including exhibit Q). (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Robert Lindsley case--Darlean Ambrose interview (exhibit A). (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Robert Lindsley case--Samuel S. Shepherd interview (exhibit B). (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Robert Lindsley case--Connie Salland interview (exhibit C). (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Robert Lindsley case--Johnny Glass interview (exhibit D). (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Robert Lindsley case--police 911 call (exhibit E). (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Robert Lindsley case--Joni Storms polygraph (exhibit F). (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Robert Lindsley case--list of Lindsley properties (exhibit G). (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Robert Lindsley case--Kenneth Guthrie interview (exhibit H). (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Robert Lindsley case--Adelle Guthrie interview (exhibit I). (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Robert Lindsley case--Todd Salland interview (exhibit J). (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Robert Lindsley case--James Dickenson interview (exhibit K). (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Robert Lindsley case--Timothy Kight interview (exhibit L). (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Robert Lindsley case--Harold Hatley interview (exhibit M). (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Robert Lindsley case--Audrey Lambeth interview (exhibit N). (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Robert Lindsley case--Mary Jo Strange interview (exhibit O). (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Robert Lindsley case--Joni Storms interview, includes Mrs. Strange (exhibit P). (Box 8, Folder 26)
- Series IV: Personal, 1967-2005., Extent: 1 box. (Box 9)
  Personal papers, 1967-2005, of J. T. Shropshire regarding his professional career as a clerk in the Virginia House of Delegates, as deputy clerk of the Virginia Senate, and his later private career as a consultant. Includes papers relating to his personal life, including his interest in baseball, as well as reminiscences of his service as clerk and chief of staff. Papers also cover his studies at the College of William and Mary School of Business Administration. Papers contain certificates, clippings, correspondence, invitations, notes, receipts, reminiscences, resumes, scripts, and other papers.
  - Papers, 1967-1970. (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Papers, 1971-1980. (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Papers, 1983-1989. (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Papers, 1993-1996. (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Papers, 2001-2005, undated. (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Reminiscences on service. (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - College of William and Mary School of Business Administration, 1987-1989, 1998. (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Notes. (Box 9, Folder 8)
- Series V: Politics, 1973-1992., Extent: 2 boxes. (Box 9-10)
  Politics, 1973-1992, covers the political activities of the Virginia state Democratic party and the Democratic party in the 2nd, 3rd, 5th and 6th Congressional districts. Also contains papers discussing the political campaigns of various candidates including Gerald Baliles and Doug Wilder. Also includes papers regarding the national Democratic party and the Virginia state Republican party. Papers consist of clippings, correspondence, financial records, invitations, lists, memorandums, pamphlets, posters, press releases, programs, reports, schedules, speeches, statements, and other papers.
  - Campaign correspondence, 1981-1986. (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Invitations, 1981-1989, undated. (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - General papers, 1973, 1979-1980. (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - General papers, 1981-1983. (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - General papers, 1984-1991. (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - General papers, undated. (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Gerald Baliles, 1985. (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Doug Wilder, 1980, 1983-1991, undated. (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Stump speech [Doug Wilder?]. (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - State Democratic Party Central Committee, 1989. (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - State Democratic Party Steering Committee, 1984, 1989. (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - State Democratic Convention, 1984, 1992. (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Democratic Party--2nd Congressional district, 1982. (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Democratic Party--3rd Congressional district, 1989. (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Democratic Party--5th Congressional district, 1981-1984. (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Democratic Party--6th Congressional district, 1984. (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Jefferson-Jackson Day dinners, 1982-1983, 1991, undated. (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - 1985 DNC Nationwide Public Opinion Survey: Virginia Analysis. (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Principle Findings of the 1985 DNC Public Opinion Survey. (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Democratic National Committee, 1986. (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Decisions, 1989, Census, 1990, Politics, 1992, and Beyond. (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Virginia State Republican party, 1982-1984, undated. (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Memorandum on politics and the election of 1984. (Box 10, Folder 16)
- Series VI: Diaries and address books, 1979-1988, 1995-2003., Extent: 2 boxes. (Box 11-12)
  Diaries and address books, 1979-1989, 1995-2003, contains J. T. Shropshire's diaries consisting of his personal and professional schedule and his address books containing addresses and telephone numbers of professional and personal contacts.
  - Diary, 1979. (Box 11)
  - Diary, 1980. (Box 11)
  - Diary, 1983. (Box 11)
  - Diary, 1984. (Box 11)
  - Diary, 1988. (Box 12)
  - Diary, 1989. (Box 12)
  - Diary, 1995. (Box 12)
  - Diary, 1996. (Box 12)
  - Diary, 1997. (Box 12)
  - Diary, 1998. (Box 12)
  - Diary, 2001. (Box 12)
  - Diary, 2003. (Box 12)
  - Address book. (Box 12)
  - Address book. (Box 12)
- Series VII: Inaugurals, 1966-2005., Extent: 1 box. (Box 13)
  Inaugurals, 1966-2005, contains invitations, programs, souvenirs, and tickets to the inaugurations of Virginia's governors from 1966 to 1994 (excluding 1974); presidential inaugurations of 1989 and 1997; and Richmond mayor's inauguration of 2005.
  - Inaugurals, Virginia (Mills Godwin), 1966. (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Inaugurals, Virginia (Linwood Holton), 1970. (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Inaugurals, Virginia (John N. Dalton, Charles Robb, Gerald Baliles), 1978, 1982, 1986. (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Inaugurals, Virginia (L. Douglas Wilder) (folder 1 of 2), 1990. (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Inaugurals, Virginia (L. Douglas Wilder) (folder 2 of 2), 1990. (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Inaugurals, Virginia (George Allen); United States (George H. W. Bush, Bill Clinton); Richmond mayor (L. Douglas Wilder), 1989, 1994, 1997, 2005. (Box 13, Folder 6)
- Series VIII: Photographs, 1955-1991, undated., Extent: 2 boxes. (Box 13-14)
  Photographs, 1955-1991 and undated, of Jay Shropshire, Doug Wilder, A. L. Philpott, and Edward Willey. Photographs also include images of the Virginia Senate and House of Delegates.
  - Jay Shropshire. (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Governor Doug Wilder--address to joint session of general assembly, 9 January 1991. (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Doug Wilder and Nelson Mandela. (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Doug Wilder--general. (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - A. L. Philpott. (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - A. L. Philpott lying in state in capitol, 1991. (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Senator Edward Willey's office. (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Governor John N. Dalton address to assembly, 1978. (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - General Assembly, 1955-1956. (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - General Assembly, 1960, 1962, 1964, 1966. (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - General Assembly, 1968-1969. (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - General Assembly, 1970-1972. (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Virginia Senate (folder 1 of 3), 1976. (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Virginia Senate (folder 2 of 3), 1976. (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Virginia Senate (folder 3 of 3), 1976. (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Virginia Senate, ca. 1978. (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Virginia Senate, 1980s. (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Congressional delegation breakfast, 1990. (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - General. (Box 14, Folder 11)
- Series IX: Publications, 1962, 1970-1994, 2003-2005., Extent: 2 boxes. (Box 14-15)